# SARAGADAM RAJA VENKATA, VISHWANATH

PhD in ECE, Carnegie Mellon University

5000 Forbes Ave, Porter Hall, Pittsburgh PA 15217

vishwanathsrv@cmu.edu

# RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am interested in the area of signal processing, computer vision, computational photography and machine learning. My research is aimed at a novel combination of fast algorithms as well as efficient optical setups to capture and process visual information that pushes the boundaries of spatial, spectral and temporal resolutions.

# Conference Papers

- V Saragadam, J Wang, X Li, A Sankaranarayanan, "Compressive spectral anomaly detection", International Conference on Computational Photography, 2017
- V Saragadam, A Sankaranarayanan, X Li, "Cross-scale predictive dictionaries for image and video restoration", International Conference on Image Processing, 2016

### JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

- V Saragadam, and A Sankaranarayanan, "KRISM Krylov Subspace-based optical computation of hyperspectral images", (under review), Transactions on Graphics, 2018
- V Saragadam, A Sankaranarayanan, X Li, "Cross-scale predictive dictionaries", Transactions on Image Processing, 2018

# **EDUCATION**

### Carnegie Mellon University

2014 -

- Doctorate of Philosophy in Electrical and Computer Engineering.
- Advised by Prof. Aswin Sankaranarayanan and Prof. Xin Li

#### Carnegie Mellon University

2014 - 2016

- Master of Sciences in Electrical and Computer Engineering.

#### Indian Institute of Technology Madras

2010 - 2014

- B.Tech(Hons.) in Electrical Engineering with minor degree in Operations Research.
- Cumulative Grade Point Average: 9.42/10
- Recipient of Siemens award for highest GPA in electrical engineering 2014 batch.

### Teaching experience

- Recipient of the Outstanding Teaching Assistant award of 2018 in the ECE department at Carnegie Mellon University.
- Head Teaching assistant for "Signals and Systems" at Carnegie Mellon University under Prof. Pulkit Grover and Prof. Byron Yu. I was responsible for recitation sessions, homeworks, and managing the teaching assistants group.
- Teaching assistant for "Signals and Systems" at Carnegie Mellon University under Prof. Pulkit Grover and Prof. Byron Yu. I was responsible for recitation sessions and setting questions for homeworks.
- Teaching assistant for "Image and Video Processing" at Carnegie Mellon University under Prof. Aswin Sankaranarayanan. I was responsible for recitation sessions and setting questions for homeworks.

#### Snap Inc., New York City, New York

May - August 2018

- Under the guidance of Shree Nayar, and Prof. Mohit Gupta (University Wisconsin Madison)
- Worked on Augmented Reality hardware.

### Intel corporation, Santa Clara, California

May - August 2015

- Worked on convolutional sparse coding for recognition tasks
- Fast implementation of convolutional sparse coding for handling massive training data using multithreading.

#### Maschinenfabrik Reinhausen GmbH, Regensburg, Germany

May - July 2013

- Wrote XML validation script for Bachmann platform.
- Ported tap changing monitoring system to Bachmann platform.
- Created emulation module for voltages and temperatures for software modules.
- Created automation system for documentation of software modules.

# Sasken Communication Technologies, Chennai, India

May - July 2012

- Ported Boot 2 Gecko, Mozilla's web based mobile operating system to Huawei U8150.
- Compiled Gecko render engine and Linux kernel to ARM platform.

### Conferences and workshops

- Invited talk at University of Maryland College Park on "KRISM Krylov subspace-based optical computing of hyperspectral images", 2018
- Invited talk at Johns Hopkins University on "KRISM Krylov subspace-based optical computing of hyperspectral images", 2018
- Presented demo on "KRISM Krylov subspace-based optical computing of hyperspectral images" at International Conference on Computational Photography, 2018, held in Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh.
- Presented paper on "Compressive spectral anomaly detection" at International Conference on Computational photography, 2017, held in Stanford University, California.
- Invited talk at Indian Institute of Sciences, Bangalore, India on "Cross-scale predictive dictionaries", 2017
- Invited talk at International Institute of Information Technology, Hyderabad, India on "Sparse representations and its applications", 2017
- Presented paper on "Cross-scale predictive dictionaries for image and video restoration" at International Conference on Image Processing, 2016, held in Phoenix, Arizona.
- Volunteered at International Conference of Computational Photography, 2015, held in Houston, Texas.
- Participated in IEEE SPS Summer School on Signal Processing and Machine Learning for Big Data, 2016, held in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.
- Winner of third prize in IEEE All India Young Engineers Humanitarian challenge, 2012, held in Bangalore, India.
- Presented a poster on "Controlling a two-degree of freedom pantograph plotter" at National Conference on Mechanisms and Machines, 2011, held in Chennai, India.

#### Positions of Responsibility

- Web chair for International Conference on Computational Photography 2018, held in Carnegie Mellon University.
- Volunteer for "Camera workshop" as part of Gelfand Outreach Program at CMU in 2016 and 2017.
- Member of Avanti Fellows. I mentored a high school student for appearing in competitive exams for undergrad in engineering.
- National Service Scheme, IIT Madras. Volunteer from 2010-2011. Project reprsentative for "Making toys from trash" from 2011-2012. Advisory committee member from 2012-2014.
- IEEE student memeber of Signal Processing Society.

### SCHOLASTIC ACHIEVEMENTS

• Recipient of Prabhu and Poonam Goel Graduate fellowship for the academic year 2018/19 at Carnegie Mellon University.

- Recipient of the Outstanding Teaching Assistant award of 2018 in the ECE department at Carnegie Mellon University.
- . Recipient of Dean's tuition fellowship for graduate studies at Carnegie Mellon University.
- Recipient of Siemen's award for highest GPA in electrical engineering in IIT Madras.
- Recipient of the Shri V Rajagopalan Memorial award for outstanding performance in  $3^{rd}$  and  $4^{th}$  semesters in electrical engineering.
- Recipient of the M Sankaraih and M Saradah scholarship for outstanding performance in sophomore year.
- Recipient of the CBSE merit scholarship for professional studies 2010 2014.
- Qualified for the DAAD WISE scholarship 2013 for internship at TU Bremen.
- Qualified for the S N Bose scholars program 2013 for internship at University of Wisconsin Madison.
- Secured 155<sup>th</sup> rank in IIT Joint Entrance Examination 2010 among 470,000 students.
- Selected for the *Kishore Vaigyanik Prothsahan Yojana*(KVPY) scholars program 2010 for higher studies in basic sciences, awarded by Department of Science and Technology, Government of India.

#### SKILLS

#### . Computer languages:

- Proficient at coding in C, C++, Python, Cython and Matlab.
- Working knowledge of VHDL, Verilog, Assembly (8051, ARM), CUDA and PLC ladder logic.

### . Computer tools and platforms:

- Proficient at Microsoft Office, Autodesk 3ds Max, Spice opus and LATEX.
- Working knowledge of AutoCAD, Xilinx IDE, keil  $\mu$ Vision, Modelsim and Bachmann PLC platform.
- Operating systems: Microsoft Windows, Linux(Debian, Red hat, Arch).

# OTHER PROJECTS AND ARTICLES

# Optimal measurement matrix for signals in a union of subspaces

March - May 2014

- Worked on obtaining optimal measurement matrix with least number of measurements for a signal lying in a finite union of finite dimensional subspaces.
- Part of Convex Optimization course at Carnegie Mellon University.

#### Detecting text in natural images

September - December 2014

- Worked on detecting text in natural images as part of the computer vision course at Carnegie Mellon University.
- Code hosted at  $\t ttps://github.com/satwikkottur/ImageTextDetector$

### Utilizing motion sensors for some image processing applications

August 2013 - May 2014

- Worked on image registration, image deblurring, and depth estimation on mobile device using motion sensors data, under the guidance of  $Prof.\ A\ N\ Rajagopalan^1$
- Thesis can be downloaded at www.ece.cmu.edu/~vsaragad/academics/report.pdf

#### Accessible Reading material

May 2011 - December 2012

- Developed a low cost semi autonomous assistive device for tactiling simple images in pre-literacy and early literacy books for visually impaired children under the guidance of *Dr. Anil Prabhakar*, *Dr. Sujatha Sreenivasan and Dr. Nitin Chandrachoodan*.
- Patent pending. (Patent Application No. 4091/CHE/ 2011 "Tactograph" Date of Entry 28th November 2011 in the names of Indian Institute of Technology Madras and Chetana Charitable Trust).

# Canny edge detection using Python and SCIPY

September 2012

- Published an article on implementing the canny edge detector in python in "Linux For You", a famous open source magazine in India.

#### Image segmentation using graph partitioning

August - November 2012

- Worked on segmenting objects in images using random walk models and community detection as a part of Introduction to social networks course under the guidance of Dr. Andrew Thangaraj and Dr. Krishna Jagannathan.
- Code hosted at https://github.com/vishwa91/grimp.

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>1</sup>Department of Electrical Engineering, IIT Madras

- Made an analog spectrum analyzer based on mixer as part of Analog circuits lab.
- Spectrum analyzer could detect sinusoids distinctly for frequencies between 500Hz and 5kHz.

# RELEVANT COURSES

### Carnegie Mellon University

- Applied Stochastic Processes
- Linear Systems
- Convex Optimization
- Estimation, detection and identification
- Computer Vision

#### Indian Institute of Technology Madras

- Networks and systems
- Analog and digital signal processing
- Introduction to communication networks
- Introduction to data structures and algorithms
- Communication systems
- Analog IC design

- Intermediate Statistics
- Compressive sensing and sparse approximation
- Information theory
- Physics based methods in vision
- Advanced Digital Signal Processing
- Computer Aided Designing for electrical engineering
- Digital communication
- Communication networks
- Digital IC design
- Speech signal processing
- Analog and digital filter design